Yongming Fan

fan322@purdue.edu

http://www.yongming.fan

J +1 (812) 327-8479

Research Interest

My research interests lie at the intersection of applied cryptography, zero knowledge proof, protocol security evaluation, privacy, and software security. Specifically, I am intrigued by the potential of zk-SNARKs to enhance privacy and efficiency in various applications. I also have a keen interest in evaluating the security of cryptographic protocols software implementation, ensuring they are robust against emerging threats and vulnerabilities. Overall, my research aims to bridge the gap between theoretical cryptography and practical security solutions, addressing critical challenges in the rapidly evolving digital landscape.

Education

2020 – Present Ph.D. Computer Science Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN Advisor: Christina Garman

2018 – 2020 M.S. Computer Science, Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN Advisor: *David Crandall*

Thesis title: Segmentation of Retinal Optic from a New Approach Hough Transform

2014 – 2018 B.A. Mathematics, Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN B.S. Computer Science, Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Research Experience

Aug 2020 – Present Research Assistant Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

May 2018 – Aug 2018 **Visiting Scholar** York University, Toronto, ON

Aug 2018 – Jul 2020 Research Assistant Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Jan 2017 – May 2017 Undergraduate Researcher Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Professional Service

Conference Leadership/Organization

Program Committees

2024 **Reviewer**, International Journal of Applied Cryptography

2023 Reviewer, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics

PC Member, ICLR Workshop on Backdoor Attacks and Defenses in Machine Learning

Sub-Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Medical Artificial Intelligence

2022 **Sub-Reviewer**, Financial Cryptography and Data Security

Research Publications

Publications

Yongming Fan, Yuquan Xu, and Christina Garman, "Snarkprobe: An automated security analysis framework for zksnark implementations," in *International Conference on Applied Cryptography and Network Security*, Springer, 2024.

- Xurui Li, Yue Qin, Rui Zhu, Tianqianjin Lin, **Yongming Fan**, Yangyang Kang, Kaisong Song, Fubang Zhao, Changlong Sun, Haixu Tang, *et al.*, "Stinmatch: Semi-supervised semantic-topological iteration network for financial risk detection via news label diffusion," in *Proceedings of the 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*, 2023, pp. 9304–9315.
- Zhixin Li, Rui Zhu, Zihao Wang, Jiale Li, Kaiyuan Liu, Yue Qin, **Yongming Fan**, Mingyu Gu, Zhihui Lu, Jie Wu, Hongfeng Chai, Xiaofeng Wang, and Haixu Tang, "Fairfix: Enhancing fairness of pre-trained deep neural networks with scarce data resources," in *International Conference on Smart Computing and Communication*, Springer, 2023, (Best Student Paper Award).
- Yongming Fan, "Segmentation of retinal optic from a new approach hough transform," M.S. thesis, Indiana University Bloomington, May 2020.

Submitted

- **Yongming Fan**, Priyam Biswas, and Christina Garman, "Sok: A systematic study of cryptographic function identification approaches in binaries," Currently under review, 2023.
- Yongming Fan and Christina Garman, "Sigmagraph: Using graph algorithms to verify sigma protocols," Currently under review, 2023.

Employment History

Aug 2020 – Dec 2023	■ Teaching Assistant Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN
Aug 2019 – Aug 2020	Software Developer Indiana University School of Optometry, Bloomington, IN
Apr 2018 – June 2020	Application Developer Pervasive Technology Institute, Bloomington, IN
May 2017 – Aug 2017	Assistant Registrar Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN
Aug 2016 – Dec 2017	■ Teaching Assistant Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Teaching

Fall 2022	CS 52600 Information Security Assistant Instructor with Prof. Christina Garman at Purdue University
Spring 2022	CS 50023 Data Engineering I Assistant Instructor with Prof. Ruby Tahboub at Purdue University
Fall 2020	CS 50023 Data Engineering I Assistant Instructor with Prof. Ruby Tahboub at Purdue University
Fall 2019	CSCI-A 202 Introduction to Programming II Assistant Instructor with Prof. Rod Stark at Indiana University Bloomington
Fall 2017	CSCI-A 290 Topics in Programming: Arduino Assistant Instructor with Prof. Olgun Sadik at Indiana University Bloomington
	CSCI-A 290 Topics in Programming: Python Assistant Instructor with Prof. Olgun Sadik at Indiana University Bloomington
	CSCI-A 201 Introduction to Programming I Assistant Instructor with Prof. Mitja Hmeljak at Indiana University Bloomington
Summer 2017	CSCI-A 201 Introduction to Programming I Assistant Instructor with Prof. Olgun Sadik at Indiana University Bloomington
Spring 2017	CSCI-A 201 Introduction to Programming I Assistant Instructor with Prof. Erik Wennstrom at Indiana University Bloomington
Fall 2016	CSCI-A 201 Introduction to Programming I Assistant Instructor with Prof. Mitja Hmeljak at Indiana University Bloomington

Miscellaneous Experience

Awards and Achievements

Intelligent Systems for Sustainable Urban Mobility Travel Expenses
Total: Can\$1,500 from Intelligent Systems for Sustainable Urban Mobility (ISSUM)

Vision: Science to Applications AwardsTotal: Can\$7,500 from Vision: Science to Applications (VISTA), York University

Graduate Student Fellowship

Total: \$39,041 from University Information Technology Services (UITS), Indiana University

Anurag & Aruna Mendhekar Scholarship

Total: \$2,000 from Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, Indiana University Bloomington

Software Development

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN
SNARKProbe: An Automated Security Analysis Framework for zkSNARK Implementation
(https://github.com/fanym919/snarkprobe)

Indiana University, Bloomignton, IN

DLO Post Processing: Glaucomatous Blind Spots Analysis and Blood Vessel Calibration

System

York University, Toronto, ON
Trans-Plan: An Intelligent Systems for Sustainable Urban Mobility
(https://www.elderlab.yorku.ca/research/systems/)